Maxwell Patterson

mmpatterson94@gmail.com | 716-525-0522 | Chicago, Illinois

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxwell-patterson/ | Website: https://mmpatterson.github.io/

SUMMARY

Data Science and Visualization professional with a background as an IT Consultant. Earned a certificate in Data Science from Northwestern University and have 3+ years of professional experience in data analysis. Educational background also includes a B.S. in mathematics and physics from Dickinson College. Experienced in Python, SQL, NoSQL, and JavaScript to create full-stack applications. My technical skills, combined with my experience in collaborative, deadline-driven environments, make me a strong addition to any data analysis team.

EDUCATION

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

Certificate, Data Science Boot Camp

February 2020

DICKINSON COLLEGE

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics and Physics

May 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python (pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Flask, scikit-learn, PySpark), SQL (MSSQL, PostgreSQL),
 JavaScript (plotly, D3, Leaflet), R
- Tools: Machine Learning (linear regression, logistic regression, decision trees, random forest, k-nearest neighbors),
 Tableau, HTML5, CSS3, Jupyter Notebooks, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Visual Studio, Git, SQL
 Server Management Studio, REST APIs

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NIELSEN Chicago, IL

Analytical Framework Consultant

August 2019 - Present

- Work with client and offshore development team to transition databases from legacy systems to newer products
- Use Python to analyze variance in sales information between databases
- Work with data scientists to create machine learning application that predicts a product's characteristics

REVENUE SOLUTIONS, INC.

Chicago, IL

IT Consultant

December 2017 - August 2019

Associate IT Consultant

September 2016 - December 2017

- Received company award for excellence in communication with the client
- Provided Production support for web applications that increase tax processing efficiency for state, city, and county governments
- Worked with clients' business and technical leads to create and update software requirements specifications (SRS) for multiple custom interfaces involving ETL
- Used SQL Server Data Tools to create SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) packages
- Created process flow diagrams using Microsoft Visio
- Used MSSQL to query and monitor large data loads

INTERCOLLEGIATE ATHLETICS

DICKINSON COLLEGE		Carlisle, PA
•	NCAA Division III Cross Country Team	2012 - 2014
•	NCAA Division III Track & Field Team	2012 - 2015
•	Student Assistant Coach, NCAA Division III Cross Country and Track & Field Teams	2015 - 2016